A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1969-1970
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1969-1970
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.731
This collection consists of 29,400 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 30 July 1973.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by Edgar F. Shannon, Jr., the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of general and committee files.
Separated Material
Box 28 has been removed from the collection. Its original contents, Reports of the Institutional Analysis Office, have been re-accessioned as RG-4/4/1.771.
Contents List
- Series I: General Files, 1969-1970
  - "A - Al" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - "Am" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - "An - Az" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Admissions - General 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Admissions - Reports 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Admissions - Applicants, "A - Z" 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Advisory Panel on ROTC Affairs 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Air Force and Air Force ROTC 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Albemarle County Public Schools 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Association - General 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Alumni - Medical 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Fund 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Alumni News 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - Alumni - Speeches 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Charlottesville Albemarle Chapter 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Clinch Valley 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Atlanta Chapter 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Louisiana Chapter 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Mary Washington College 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Maryland 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Richmond Chapter 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - Alumni Association - Washington 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - American Association of State Colleges and Universities 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - American Association of University Professors 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - American Association of University Professors - Membership Committee 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - American Council on Education - Board of Directors, Calendar - June 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - American Council on Education - Board of Directors, Calendar, October 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - American Council on Education report: "Black Students in American Colleges"1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - American Council on Education report: "National Norms for... Freshmen"1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - American Council on Education 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - American Council on Education - Circulars 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Annual Reports 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Applications for positions, "A - Z" 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Architecture - General 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Architecture - Personnel 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Army - General 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Army - ROTC (Military Science) (see also ROTC) 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's School 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Art 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Art - Graduate Institute of Art History 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Art Commission 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Colleges 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Universities 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Universities - Membership Committee 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Astronomy 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Athletics - General 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Athletics - Finances 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Athletics - Football 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Athletics - ACC 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Athletics - NCAA 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Athletics - 3 - 3 -2 Committee 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Athletics - Invitations to Games 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Athletics - Football: Clemson - 20 September 1969 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Athletics - Football: Duke - 27 September 1969 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - Football: North Carolina State - Commonwealth Day, 18 October 1969 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - Football: North Carolina - 1 November 1969 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - Football: Wake Forest - 8 November 1969 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Athletics - Personnel 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Atlantic Council of the United States 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Atomic Energy Commission 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Atomic Energy Commission report: Annual Report to Congress, 19691969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Atomic Energy Commission report (supplement): Fundamental... Research, 19691969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Audit Reports 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - "B - Bm" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - "Bn - Bz" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Biology - General 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Budget Office - Capital Outlay 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Budget - Miscellaneous Information 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Budget - Requests 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Budget - Director's Office 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Building Program 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Buildings and Grounds - General 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Bursar 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - Business and Finance - Vice President 9 January 1980 (formerly Comptroller) 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - Calendar of Events 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - Cavalier Daily 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Center for Advanced Studies 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Center for Research and Innovations in Buildings 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Center for the Study of Science, Technology, and Public Policy 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Center for... Public Policy report: Virginia's Urban Corridor1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Center for the Study of Applied Ethics 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Chemistry - General 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Children's Rehabilitation Center (see also Rehabilitation Center) 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Chronicle of Higher Education 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Civil Defense 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Civil Rights 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Classics 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Clinch Valley College - General 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Clinch Valley College - Building Program 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Clinch Valley College - Monthly Reports (folder empty) 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Clinch Valley College - Personnel 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - College Entrance Examination Board 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Committees (see boxes 67-69) 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Community Colleges 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Computer Center 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Consultative Resource Center of school Desegregation of U.Va. 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Council of presidents (see also Tax Study Commission) 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Council of Southern Universities (see also Southern Fellowship Fund) 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - "Da - De" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - "Df - Dz" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - Danforth Foundation 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - Darlington School, Board of Trustees 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - Data Processing 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - Deans Luncheons 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - Development and Public Affairs 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - Ditchley Foundation 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - Economics 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - Education 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - Educational TV 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - Endowment Fund 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - Engineering and Buildings (Hamner) 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - Engineering and Applied Science - General 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - Engineering School report: Research Laboratories for Engineering Sciences 19691969-1970 (Box 16)
  - English 1969-1970 (Box 17)
  - Enrollment (see also Registrar) 1969-1970 (Box 17)
  - Environmental Science 1969-1970 (Box 17)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 17)
  - Faculty - General 1969-1970 (Box 17)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - General 1969-1970 (Box 17)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel, "A - M" 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel, "N - Z" 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Faculty Orientation and Reception 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences, Committees of 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Fair Labor Standards Act 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Federal Executive Institute 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - General 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Cross 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Du Pont 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Love 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Finals - 1970 1969-1970 (Box 19)
  - Founder's Day 1969-1970 (Box 19)
  - Financial Aid to Students 1969-1970 (Box 19)
  - Fine Arts Center 1969-1970 (Box 19)
  - William B. Fitzgerald Foundation 1969-1970 (Box 20)
  - Ford Foundation 1969-1970 (Box 20)
  - Foreign Student Advisor 1969-1970 (Box 20)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly 1969-1970 (Box 20)
  - General Studies - General 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - Central Virginia Center for General Studies 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - General Studies - Eastern Shore Branch 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - General Studies - Easter Shore - Personnel 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - General Studies - Hampton Roads Center 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - General Studies - Hampton Roads - Personnel (folder empty) 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - General Studies - Lynchburg Branch 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - General Studies - Lynchburg - Personnel (folder empty) 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - General Studies - Northern Virginia Branch 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - General Studies - Patrick Henry Branch 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - General Studies - Richmond Center 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - General Studies - Roanoke Center 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - General Studies - Southwest Virginia Center 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - Geology 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - George Mason College 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - George Mason College - Proposals by Edgar F. Shannon, Jr.: 1969-1970 (Box 21)
    - Program for the Degree of Master of Science in Biology (Box 21)
    - Program... Bachelor of Arts with Major in Sociology (Box 21)
    - Program... Master of Education in Elementary Education (Box 21)
    - Proposal... Bachelor of Science with major in Mathematics (Box 21)
    - Proposal... Bachelor of Science with major in Physics (Box 21)
  - George Mason College - Personnel 1969-1970 (Box 22)
  - Gifts and Grants - Correspondence 1969-1970 (Box 22)
  - Gifts and Grants, 1 May 1970 - 1 July 1970 1969-1970 (Box 22)
  - Gifts and Grants, 1 February 1970 - 1 May 1970 1969-1970 (Box 23)
  - Gifts and Grants, 1 November 1969 - 1 February 1970 1969-1970 (Box 23)
  - Gifts and Grants, 1 July 1969 - 1 November 1969 1969-1970 (Box 24)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1969-1970 (Box 24)
  - Governor's Office 1969-1970 (Box 24)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1969-1970 (Box 25)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration 1969-1970 (Box 25)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration - Personnel 1969-1970 (Box 25)
  - Graduate Business Sponsors 1969-1970 (Box 25)
  - Graphics 1969-1970 (Box 25)
  - Guggenheim Foundation 1969-1970 (Box 25)
  - Gwathmey Award 1969-1970 (Box 25)
  - "H" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Harvard Graduate Society Council 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Higher Education Act of 1965 (folder empty) 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Higher Education Act - Title I 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Higher Education Act - Title II (folder empty) 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Higher Education Act - Title III 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Higher Education Act - Title IV 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Higher Education Act - Title V 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Higher Education Act - Title VI 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Highway Department 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - History 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Honor System and Honor Committee 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Honors Program 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Housing 1969-1970 (Box 27)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 27)
  - Information Services 1969-1970 (Box 27)
  - Institute of Government 1969-1970 (Box 27)
  - Institutional Analysis Office 1969-1970 (Box 27)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Statistical Information, U.Va. - Nov. 1969 1969-1970 (Box 27)
  - Institutional Analysis Office: Analysis of U.Va. Buildings 1969-1970 (Box 27)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Financial Aid to Graduate Students at the University of Virginia, 1968-1969.1969-1970 (Box 28)
    Removed and accessioned as RG-4/4/1.771
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Profile of Undergraduate Students in Phi Beta Kappa and the Raven Society.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Follow-Up of Doctor of Education Degree Recipients, 1952-1969.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: U.Va. Semester Hours - Credit Produced, First Semesters 1968, 1969.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Distribution of Credit Hours... by School and Faculty Rank, First Semester 1969.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Space Analysis, Cocke Hall, March 1970.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Applicants for Admission from Virginia Public High Schools, fall 1969.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Distribution of Undergraduate and Graduate Grades, First Semester 1969.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Graduate Degrees in June and August, 1969-1969 by fields and advisors.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Ratios of Students to Teaching-Research Faculty by School and Rank.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Projected Housing Needs for Single Students 1970-1975.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Summary of AAUP Annual Compensation Survey 1969-1970.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Academic Achievement... of Single Undergraduates, 1968-1969.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Analysis of... Undergraduate Applicants to the College of Arts and Sciences, Architecture, Engineering, 1966-1969... Enrolled, Not Enrolled, Denied.. .1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Admissions Report for Falls 1969 and 19701969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Academic Record of Students... 1962-1969... Advanced Placement Exams.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Selected Characteristics of Negro Undergraduates, 1966-1969.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Analysis of Bachelor Degree Recipients, School of Nursing, 1969.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Space Use by School of General Studies, June 1970.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Space Analysis: Randall, Wilson, Old Cabell, New Cabell, Rouss, Cocke.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Institutional Analysis Office report: Profile of Students Who Withdrew from... College of Arts and Sciences, September 1969 to March 1970.1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Invitations - "A" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "B" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "C" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "D" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "E" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "F" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "G" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "H" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "I" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "J" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "K" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "L" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "M" 1969-1970 (Box 29)
  - Invitations - "N" 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "O" 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "P" 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "Q" (folder empty) 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "R" 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "S" 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "T" 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "U" 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "V" 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "W" 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - Invitations - "X, Y, Z" 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1969-1970 (Box 31)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation - Minutes 1969-1970 (Box 31)
  - Jefferson Society 1969-1970 (Box 31)
  - Thomas Jefferson Center (folder empty) 1969-1970 (Box 31)
  - Judge Advocate General's (J.A.G.) School (see also Army - J.A.G.) 1969-1970 (Box 31)
  - Judiciary Committee 1969-1970 (Box 31)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 31)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 31)
  - Law - Applicants 1969-1970 (Box 31)
  - Law - General 1969-1970 (Box 32)
  - Law - Alumni Day 1969-1970 (Box 32)
  - Law report: U.Va. Council on Legal Educational Opportunity, Summer Inst. 19691969-1970 (Box 32)
  - Legal Advisor 1969-1970 (Box 32)
  - Legal - Estates 1969-1970 (Box 32)
  - Law publication: Virginia Law Weekly1969-1970 (Box 32)
  - Lectures 1969-1970 (Box 32)
  - Liberal Arts 1969-1970 (Box 32)
  - Library - General 1969-1970 (Box 33)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 33)
  - McIntire Fund (see also Legal) 1969-1970 (Box 33)
  - McGregor Fund 1969-1970 (Box 33)
  - "Ma - Me" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 33)
  - "Mi - Mz" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 34)
  - Madison Hall (YMCA) 1969-1970 (Box 34)
  - Mariner's Museum report: Organization of the Mariner's Museum 19691969-1970 (Box 34)
  - Mariner's Museum 1969-1970 (Box 34)
  - Marine Science 1969-1970 (Box 35)
  - Markle Foundation 1969-1970 (Box 35)
  - Mary Washington College 1969-1970 (Box 35)
  - Mary Washington College - Personnel 1969-1970 (Box 35)
  - Mary Washington College report: Annual Budget 1970-19711969-1970 (Box 35)
  - Mary Washington College - Weekly Bulletins 1969-1970 (Box 35)
  - Mary Washington College - Alumnae News1969-1970 (Box 36)
  - Mary Washington College report: Biennial Budget 1970-19721969-1970 (Box 36)
  - Mary Washington College - Building Program 1969-1970 (Box 36)
  - Mary Washington College - Financial 1969-1970 (Box 36)
  - Mathematics 1969-1970 (Box 36)
  - Medical Center - General 1969-1970 (Box 36)
  - Medical School Library report: Virginia Union List of Biomedical Serials1969-1970 (Box 36)
  - Medical Center - Hospital 1969-1970 (Box 36)
  - Medical Center - Personnel 1969-1970 (Box 36)
  - Medical Center - Medical School 1969-1970 (Box 37)
  - Medical Center - Monthly Statistical Reports 1969-1970 (Box 37)
  - Medical Center - Operating Budget and Reports 1969-1970 (Box 37)
  - Medical Center - Rehabilitation and Training Center 1969-1970 (Box 37)
  - Medical Center - Reports on Current Operations 1969-1970 (Box 37)
  - Medical Center - Nursing 1969-1970 (Box 38)
  - Medical Center - Nursing - Personnel 1969-1970 (Box 38)
  - James Monroe Museum and Library 1969-1970 (Box 38)
  - Mountain Lake Conference 1969 1969-1970 (Box 38)
  - [?] re: Brewster speech at George Washington University Commencement, and Mountain Lake meeting of U.Va. Student Council. 1969-1970 (Box 38)
  - Magazine: September 1969 Harper's Magazine article: Survival U. by Fisher, Book: Education and the Barricades by Charles Frankel 1969-1970 (Box 38)
  - Music 1969-1970 (Box 38)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 39)
  - NASA (see also VARC) [special file 4137 - AC] 1969-1970 (Box 39)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges 1969-1970 (Box 40)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges: Proceedings 19691969-1970 (Box 40)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - International 1969-1970 (Box 41)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1969-1970 (Box 41)
  - National Defense Education Act (Student Loan) 1969-1970 (Box 41)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities 1969-1970 (Box 41)
  - National Historical Publications Commission 1969-1970 (Box 41)
  - National Science Foundation 1969-1970 (Box 41)
  - National Science Foundation - Institutional Grant for Science 1969-1970 (Box 41)
  - NSF - Advisory Committee of Institutional Relations 1969-1970 (Box 42)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation 1969-1970 (Box 42)
  - National Science Foundation report: The Physical Sciences 1970 1969-1970 (Box 42)
  - U.S. House of Rep's. report: Hearings 1968-1969 on Status of Naval Ships 1969-1970 (Box 42)
  - National War College 1969-1970 (Box 42)
  - Navy - General 1969-1970 (Box 42)
  - Navy - ROTC 1969-1970 (Box 42)
  - Navy League of the United States 1969-1970 (Box 43)
  - Newcomb Hall (see also University Union) 1969-1970 (Box 43)
  - Newcomen Society 1969-1970 (Box 43)
  - Newsletter 1969-1970 (Box 43)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1969-1970 (Box 43)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 43)
  - Office Invoices, 1 February 1970 - 1 July 1970 1969-1970 (Box 44)
  - Office Invoices, 1 July 1969 - 31 January 1970 1969-1970 (Box 44)
  - Office Travel 1969-1970 (Box 44)
  - Office of Institutional Research 1969-1970 (Box 45)
  - "P - Ph" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 45)
  - "Pi - Pz" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 45)
  - Personnel Correspondence 1969-1970 (Box 45)
  - Personnel, "A - Z" 1969-1970 (Box 46)
  - Personnel - Employee Relations 1969-1970 (Box 46)
  - Personnel - Fringe Benefits Sheets 1969-1970 (Box 46)
  - Personal Profiles 1969-1970 (Box 46)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1969-1970 (Box 46)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Council 1969-1970 (Box 46)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Associates 1969-1970 (Box 46)
  - Philosophy 1969-1970 (Box 46)
  - Physics - General 1969-1970 (Box 47)
  - Planning Department 1969-1970 (Box 47)
  - Project Status Reports 1969-1970 (Box 47)
  - Provost of the University 1969-1970 (Box 47)
  - Purchasing 1969-1970 (Box 47)
  - Public Affairs 1969-1970 (Box 47)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 48)
  - Questionnaires and Inquiries 1969-1970 (Box 48)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 48)
  - Radiation Protection 1969-1970 (Box 48)
  - Radio 1969-1970 (Box 48)
  - Raven Society 1969-1970 (Box 48)
  - Recommendations, "A - Z" 1969-1970 (Box 48)
  - Registrar - General 1969-1970 (Box 48)
  - Registrar - Student Reports 1969-1970 (Box 48)
  - Religious Studies 1969-1970 (Box 48)
  - Romance Languages 1969-1970 (Box 48)
  - ROTC (see also Army) 1969-1970 (Box 49)
  - "S - Sl" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 50)
  - "Sm - Sz" Miscellaneous 1969-1970 (Box 50)
  - Salaries (see also Personnel) 1969-1970 (Box 51)
  - Security 1969-1970 (Box 51)
  - Seely, Charles S. 1969-1970 (Box 51)
  - University Senate 1969-1970 (Box 51)
  - Senate Finance Committee - Arbitration Bonds, 25 September 1969 1969-1970 (Box 51)
  - Seven Society 1969-1970 (Box 51)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities 1969-1970 (Box 51)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools 1969-1970 (Box 51)
  - Southern Regional Education Board 1969-1970 (Box 52)
  - Southern Fellowship Fund 1969-1970 (Box 52)
  - Southern University Conference 1969-1970 (Box 52)
  - Space Utilization (see also Institutional Analysis) 1969-1970 (Box 53)
  - Speeches 1969-1970 (Box 53)
    Includes Shannon's anti-war speech, delivered on the steps of the Rotunda, May 10, 1970.
  - Speech and Drama 1969-1970 (Box 53)
  - Sponsored Programs 1969-1970 (Box 53)
  - State Board of Education 1969-1970 (Box 53)
  - State Council of Higher Education 1969-1970 (Box 54)
  - State Council of Higher Education 1969-1970 (Box 55)
  - State Council of Higher Education - report: Criteria for establishment of State University Controlled Baccalaureate Degree Granting Institutions... in Virginia, July 19691969-1970 (Box 55)
  - Student Affairs 1969-1970 (Box 56)
  - University Flood Relief Committee 1969-1970 (Box 56)
  - Student Council - Minutes 1969-1970 (Box 57)